Viet Quoc Pham

Personal Data

OFFICE: 4.10, CONNECT Centre, 34 Westland Row, 8PRX+RV Dublin, Ireland

PHONE: (+353) 083 475 5354 EMAIL: viet.pham@tcd.ie

Personal Site: https://www.scss.tcd.ie/viet.pham

PROFILES: Google Scholar, ResearchGate, Publons, Scopus, LinkedIn, and ORCID

OVERVIEW

I am an assistant professor in networks and distributed systems in the School of Computer Science and Statistics at Trinity College Dublin, the University of Dublin, Ireland. I am also associated with CONNECT, an SFI centre for future networks and communications, and AdvanceCRT, an SFI centre for research training in advanced networks for sustainable societies, where I lead the COmputing, Intelligence, and Networking (COIN) research group. My research interest is to employ an arsenal of mathematical tools such as convex optimization, game theory, and machine learning to design, analyze, and optimize complex networks and applications such as cloud edge computing, 6G wireless networks, metaverse, blockchain, and wireless AI. While my work addresses research aspects of the interplay between AI and wireless, I am also interested in multidisciplinary research to leverage expertise from different sciences and disciplines.

EDUCATION

Aug. 2017	Doctor of Engineering in Telecommunications, Inje University, Kimhae, Korea
	Prize: Best Ph.D. Dissertation Award, Ranking #1 in Engineering
Aug. 2015	Master of Science in Telecommunications, Inje University, Kimhae, Korea
Aug. 2013	Bachelor of Science in Electronics and Telecommunications,
	Hanoi University of Science and Technology, Hanoi, Vietnam

ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

Jan. 2023 - Current	Assistant Professor in Networks and Distributed Systems,
	School of Computer Science and Statistics, Trinity College Dublin, Ireland
Jan. 2023 - Current	TCD Supervisor, SFI ADVANCE CRT, Ireland
Jan. 2023 - Current	Associate Investigator, SFI CONNECT, Ireland
Jan. 2020 - Jan. 2023	Research Professor, Pusan National University, Korea
Mar. 2018 - Dec. 2019	Research Professor, Changwon National University/Inje University, Korea
Sep. 2017 - Feb. 2018	Post-Doctoral Research Fellow, Kyung Hee University, Korea
Sep. 2013 - Jun. 2017	Research Assistant, Inje University, Korea
Feb. 2012 - Aug. 2013	Research Assistant, Hanoi University of Science and Technology, Vietnam

FIELDS OF RESEARCH INTEREST

- **COmputing**: cloud edge computing, aerial computing, edge of things, and edge AI.
- Intelligence: wireless AI, deep learning, deep reinforcement learning, and federated learning.
- Networking: 6G wireless, IoT, intelligent surfaces, metaverse, and blockchain.